I wanted to be a rock star.
اردت ان اصبح نجم روك
I dreamed of it, and that's all I dreamed of.
حلمت بذلك و ذلك كان كل ما احلم به
To be more accurate, I wanted to be a pop star.
لاكون اكثر دقة اردت ان اكون نجم بوب
This was in the late '80s.
هذا كان في نهاية الثمانينيات
And mostly I wanted to be the fifth member
و في الغالب اردت ان اكون العضو الخامس
of Depeche Mode or Duran Duran.
من (ديبشي مود) او (دوران دوران)
They wouldn't have me.
لكنهم لم يأخذوني
I didn't read music, but I played synthesizers and drum machines.
انا لم أدرس الموسيقى لكني عزفت على آلالات المزج و الطبل
And I grew up in this little farming town in northern Nevada.
ولقد نشأت في هذه المدينة الزراعية الصغيرة في شمال ولاية نيفادا
And I was certain that's what my life would be.
و كنت على يقين من ماذا ستكون عليه حياتي
And when I went to college at the University of Nevada, Las Vegas
و عندما ذهبت الى الكلية في جامعة نيفادا في لاس فيغاس
when I was 18,
عندما كنت في الثامنةعشرة
I was stunned to find
صدمت لمعرفتي
that there was not a Pop Star 101,
انه لم يكن هناك صف نجم بوب
or even a degree program for that interest.
او حتى برنامج شهادة بهذا الخصوص
And the choir conductor there
و قائد الجوقة هناك
knew that I sang
عرف اني اغني
and invited me to come and join the choir.
و دعاني لاتي و انضم للجوقة
And I said, "Yes, I would love to do that. It sounds great."
و قلت "نعم احب ان افعل ذلك ذلك يبدو رائعا"
And I left the room and said, "No way."
و غادرت الغرفة و قلت "هذا محال"
The choir people in my high school were pretty geeky,
اعضاء الجوقة في مدرستي الثانوية كانو غريبي الاطوار جدا
and there was no way I was going to have anything to do with those people.
ولم تكن هناك اي طريقة كانت اني سأكون لدي أي علاقة مع هؤلاء الناس.
And about a week later, a friend of mine came to me and said,
بعد حوالي اسبوع صديق لي اتى الي و قال
"Listen, you've got to join choir.
اسمع يجب ان تنضم للجوقة
At the end of the semester, we're taking a trip to Mexico,
في نهاية الفصل الدراسي سنأخذ رحلة الى المكسيك
all expenses paid.
كل التكاليف مدفوعة
And the soprano section is just full of hot girls."
وقسم الاصوات العالية فقط مليء بالفتيات المثيرات
And so I figured for Mexico and babes,
و هكذا فكرت في المكسيك والفتيات الجميلات
I could do just about anything.
بامكاني ان افعل اي شيء
And I went to my first day in choir,
و ذهبت الى يومي الاول في الجوقة
and I sat down with the basses
و جلست مع عازفي الباس
and sort of looked over my shoulder
و نظرت نوعا ما من فوق كتفي
to see what they were doing.
لارى ماذا يفعلون
They opened their scores, the conductor gave the downbeat,
و فتحو نوتاتهم الموسيقية و اعطي قائد الجوقة اشارة البداية
and boom, they launched into the Kyrie
و بوم! بدأوا في كايري
from the "Requiem" by Mozart.
من (موسيقى قداس الموتى) لموزارت
In my entire life I had seen in black and white,
في حياتي كلها كنت ارى بالابيض و الاسود
and suddenly everything was in shocking Technicolor.
و فجأة كان كل شيء بالالوان الفنية بطريقة صادمة
The most transformative experience I've ever had --
اكثر تجربة تحويلية مررت بها
in that single moment, hearing dissonance and harmony
في تلك اللحظة سماع التنافر و الانسجام
and people singing, people together,
والناس تغني الناس مع بعضها
the shared vision.
الرؤية المشتركة
And I felt for the first time in my life
و شعرت لاول مرة في حياتي
that I was part of something bigger than myself.
كنت جزءا من شيء اكبر من نفسي
And there were a lot of cute girls in the soprano section, as it turns out.
و كان هناك الكثير من الفتيات اللطيفات في قسم الاصوات العالية,كما اتضح.
I decided to write a piece for choir
قررت ان اكتب قطعة للجوقة
a couple of years later
بعد بضع سنين
as a gift to this conductor
كهدية لقائد الجوقة
who had changed my life.
الذي غير حياتي
I had learned to read music by then, or slowly learning to read music.
كنت تعلمت قراءة الموسيقى في ذلك الحين او تعلم قرائتها ببطء
And that piece was published,
و تلك القطعة تم نشرها
and then I wrote another piece, and that got published.
و عندها كتبت قطعة اخرى و تم نشرها
And then I started conducting,
ثم بدأت قيادة الجوقات
and I ended up doing my master's degree at the Juilliard School.
و انتهى بي الامر لعمل درجة الماجستير في مدرسة جوليارد
And I find myself now in the unlikely position
ووجدت نفسي في الوضع غير المرجح
of standing in front of all of you
ان اقف امامكم جميعا
as a professional classical composer and conductor.
كملحن كلاسيكي محترف وقائد جوقة
Well a couple of years ago,
حسنا قبل بعض السنين
a friend of mine emailed me
صديق لي ارسل لي
a link, a YouTube link,
رابط,رابط لموقع يوتيوب
and said, "You have got to see this."
و قال: يجب ان ترى هذا
And it was this young woman who had posted a fan video to me,
و كان امرأة شابة التي نشرت فيديو اعجاب لي
singing the soprano line
تغني سطر الاصوات العالية
to a piece of mine called "Sleep."
لمقطوعة لي اسمها (النوم)
(Video) Britlin Losee: Hi Mr. Eric Whitacre.
بريتلين لوسي:مرحبا سيد اريك ويتيكير
My name is Britlin Losee,
اسمي هو بريتلين لوسي
and this is a video
وهذا فيديو
that I'd like to make for you.
اردت عمله لك
Here's me singing "Sleep."
هذه انا اغني(النوم)
I'm a little nervous, just to let you know.
انا متوترة بعض الشيء فقط لتعلم
♫ If there are noises ♫
♫لو كان هناك ضجيج♫
♫ in the night ♫
♫في الليل♫
Eric Whitacre: I was thunderstruck.
اريك ويتيكير:كنت كمن ضربه البرق
Britlin was so innocent and so sweet,
بريتلين كانت بريئة جدا و جميلة جدا
and her voice was so pure.
و صوتها كان نقي جدا
And I even loved seeing behind her;
وحتى اني احببت رؤية ما خلفها
I could see the little teddy bear sitting on the piano behind her in her room.
كنت استطيع ان ارى دمية الدب الصغيرة تجلس على البيانو خلفها في غرفتها
Such an intimate video.
ياله من فيديو حميم
And I had this idea: if I could get 50 people
وجائتني هذه الفكرة:اذا استطعت جلب 50 شخص
to all do this same thing,
ليفعلو كلهم نفس الشيئ
sing their parts -- soprano, alto, tenor and bass --
يغنو اجزائهم-سوبرانو,التو,تينور,وباس-
wherever they were in the world, post their videos to YouTube,
اينما كانو في العالم ينشرو فيديوهاتهم الى اليوتيوب
we could cut it all together and create a virtual choir.
بامكاننا قطعها كلها مع بعضها و عمل جوقة افتراضية
So I wrote on my blog, "OMG OMG."
هكذا كتبت في مدونتي(ياالهي ياالهي)
I actually wrote, "OMG,"
كتبت (ياالهي) فعلا
hopefully for the last time in public ever.
على ما امل لاخر مرة في العلن
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I sent out this call to singers.
و ارسلت هذا النداء الى المغنين
And I made free the download of the music
و جعلت تحميل الموسيقى مجانيا
to a piece that I had written in the year 2000
لقطعة كتبتها في عام 2000
called "Lux Aurumque," which means "light and gold."
اسمها(لوكس اورومكو) التي تعني(الضوء و الذهب)
And lo and behold, people started uploading their videos.
بدأ الناس بتحميل أشرطة الفيديو الخاصة بهم.
Now I should say, before that,
الان يجب ان اقول قبل ذلك
what I did is I posted a conductor track
ما فعلته هو اني نشرت مقطع قيادة
of myself conducting.
لنفسي اقود
And it's in complete silence when I filmed it,
و كان في صمت تام حين صورته
because I was only hearing the music in my head,
لاني كنت فقط اسمع الموسيقى في رأسي
imagining the choir that would one day come to be.
متخيلا الجوقة التي ستتكون يوم من الايام
Afterwards, I played a piano track underneath
بعد ذلك عزفت مقطع بيانو تحت
so that the singers would have something to listen to.
هذا حتى يكون للمغنين شيء يستمعو له
And then as the videos started to come in ...
وبعد ذلك بدأت الفيديوهات في الوصول
(Singing)
(غناء)
This is Cheryl Ang from Singapore.
هذه شيرلي انغ من سينغافورة
This is Evangelina Etienne
هذه افانجلينا ايتين
(Singing)
(غناء)
from Massachusetts.
من ماساشوستس
Stephen Hanson from Sweden.
ستيفين هانسون من السويد
(Singing)
(غناء)
This is Jamal Walker from Dallas, Texas.
هذا جمال والكر من دالاس تكساس
There was even a little soprano solo in the piece,
وحتى كان هناك مقطع صغير لاصوات عالية في القطعة
and so I had auditions.
و هكذا عملت تجارب اداء
And a number of sopranos uploaded their parts.
و العديد من السوبرانو رفعو اجزائهم
I was told later,
تم اخباري لاحقا
and also by lots of singers who were involved in this,
وأيضا من قبل الكثير من المغنين الذين شاركوا في هذا،
that they sometimes recorded 50 or 60 different takes
انهم سجلو 50 او 60 محاولة في بعض المرات
until they got just the right take -- they uploaded it.
حتي حصلو على المحاولة الصحيحة و رفعوها
Here's our winner of the soprano solo.
هذه فائزتنا في انفراد الاصوات العالية
This is Melody Myers from Tennessee.
هذه ميلاني مايرز من تينيسي
(Singing)
(غناء)
I love the little smile she does right over the top of the note --
احب البتسامة الصغيرة التي تفعلها عند اعلى النوتة
like, "No problem, everything's fine."
مثل(لا مشكلة كل شيء بخير)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And from the crowd
و من الحشد
emerged this young man, Scott Haines.
ظهر هذا الرجل اليافع سكوت هاينز
And he said, "Listen, this is the project
و قال اسمع هذا هو المشروع
I've been looking for my whole life.
الذي كنت ابحث عنه طيلة حياتي
I'd like to be the person to edit this all together."
اريد ان اكون الشخص الذي يحرر هذا كله معا
I said, "Thank you, Scott. I'm so glad that you found me."
قلت:شكرا سكوت انا سعيد جدا انك وجدتني
And Scott aggregated all of the videos.
و جمع سكوت كل اشرطة الفيديو
He scrubbed the audio.
نقى الصوت
He made sure that everything lined up.
تاكد من كل شيء مرتب
And then we posted this video to YouTube about a year and a half ago.
و بعد ذلك نشرنا الفيديو على اليوتيوب قبل حوالي عام ونصف
This is "Lux Aurumque" sung by the Virtual Choir.
هذه(لوكس اورومكو) تغنيها الجوقة الافتراضية
(Singing)
(غناء)
I'll stop it there in the interest of time.
ساتوقف هنا في مصلحة الزمن
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you. Thank you.
شكرا شكرا
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
So there's more. There's more.
اذن هناك المزيد هناك المزيد
Thank you so much.
شكراجزيلا
And I had the same reaction you did.
و كان لدي نفس رد الفعل مثلكم
I actually was moved to tears when I first saw it.
في الواقع بكيت عندما رأيت هذا اول مرة
I just couldn't believe the poetry of all of it --
لم اصدق شاعرية كل هذا
these souls all on their own desert island,
هذه الارواح كل منها في جزيرته المعزولة
sending electronic messages in bottles to each other.
يرسلون رسائل الكترونية في زجاجات لبعضهم
And the video went viral.
و كان الفيديو مثل الفايروس
We had a million hits in the first month
حصلنا على مليون مشاهدة في الشهر الاول
and got a lot of attention for it.
و حصلنا على الكثير من الاهتمام له
And because of that, then a lot of singers started saying,
و بسبب هذا كثير من المغنين بدأو بالقول
"All right, what's Virtual Choir 2.0?"
حسنا ما هي الجوقة الافتراضية النسخة الثانية
And so I decided for Virtual Choir 2.0
و هكذا قررت للجوقة الافتراضية النسخة الثانية
that I would choose the same piece that Britlin was singing,
انني سوف اختار نفس القطعة التي كانت تغنيها بريتلين
"Sleep," which is another work
(النوم)التي كانت عمل
that I wrote in the year 2000 --
كتبته في عام 2000م
poetry by my dear friend Charles Anthony Silvestri.
كلمات صديقي العزيز شارلز انثوني سيلفستري
And again, I posted a conductor video,
و مجددا نشرت فيديو قيادة
and we started accepting submissions.
وبدأنا قبول الطلبات.
This time we got some more mature members.
و هذه المرة حصلنا على اعضاء اكبر سنا
(Singing)
(غناء)
And some younger members.
و بعض الاعضاء الاصغر سنا
(Video) Soprano: ♫ Upon my pillow ♫
سوبرانو:♫على وسادتي♫
♫ Safe in bed ♫
♫آمن في السرير♫
EW: That's Georgie from England. She's only nine.
هذه جورجي من انجلترا هي فقط في التاسعة
Isn't that the sweetest thing you've ever seen?
اليس ذلك اجمل شيء سمعتموه
Someone did all eight videos --
احدهم عمل كل الثماني فيديوهات
a bass even singing the soprano parts.
و حتى باس يغني جزء السوبرانو
This is Beau Awtin.
هذا بيو اوتين
(Video) Beau Awtin: ♫ Safe in bed ♫
بيو اوتين:♫آمن في السرير♫
EW: And our goal -- it was sort of an arbitrary goal --
و هدفنا كان نوع من هدف تعسفي
there was an MTV video where they all sang "Lollipop"
كان هناك فيديو ل ام تي في حيث غنو جميعا (لوليبوب)
and they got people from all over the world to just sing that little melody.
و حصلو على اناس من جميع انحاء العالم لغناء ذلك اللحن الصغير
And there were 900 people involved in that.
و كان هناك 900 شخص مشارك في ذلك
So I told the singers, "That's our goal.
لذا اخبرت المغنين هذا هو هدفنا
That's the number for us to beat."
هذا الرقم الذي يجب ان نتفوق عليه
And we just closed submissions January 10th,
و قد اغلقنا التقديمات فقط في العاشر من يناير
and our final tally was 2,051 videos
و حصيلتنا النهائية كانت 2,051 فيديو
from 58 different countries.
من 58 دولة مختلفة
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
From Malta, Madagascar, Thailand, Vietnam,
من مالتا مدغشقر تايلاندا فييتنام
Jordan, Egypt, Israel,
الاردن مصر اسرائيل
as far north as Alaska and as far south as New Zealand.
و بعيدا في الشمال مثل الاسكا و بعيدا في الجنوب مثل نيوزيلاندا
And we also put a page on Facebook
و ايضا وضعنا صفحة على الفيسبوك
for the singers to upload their testimonials,
للمغنين ليرفعو شهاداتهم
what it was like for them, their experience singing it.
كيف كان بالنسبة لهم تجربة غنائهم للمقطوعة
And I've just chosen a few of them here.
و اخترت البعض منهم هنا
"My sister and I used to sing in choirs together constantly.
"انا واختي كنا نغني سويا في الجوقة بشكل دائم
Now she's an airman in the air force constantly traveling.
والان هي ضابط في سلاح الجو تسافر دائما
It's so wonderful to sing together again!"
من الرائع جدا ان نغني سويا مرة اخرى"
I love the idea that she's singing with her sister.
احب فكرة انها تغني مع اختها
"Aside from the beautiful music,
"جانبا من الموسيقى الجميلة
it's great just to know I'm part of a worldwide community of people I never met before,
من الرائع فقط معرفة اني جزء من مجتمع عالمي من الناس الذين لم اقابلهم من قبل
but who are connected anyway."
لكنهم متصلون على اي حال"
And my personal favorite,
و المفضلة شخصيا لي
"When I told my husband that I was going to be a part of this,
"عندما اخبرت زوجي اني سأكون جزء من هذا
he told me that I did not have the voice for it."
قال لي ان صوتي لا يصلح لذلك"
Yeah, I'm sure a lot of you have heard that too.
نعم انا متأكد جدا كثير منكم سمع هذا ايضا
Me too.
انا ايضا
"It hurt so much, and I shed some tears,
"انه مؤلم جدا و ذرفت بعض الدموع
but something inside of me wanted to do this despite his words.
لكن شيء داخلي اراد عمل هذا بالرغم من كلماته
It is a dream come true to be part of this choir,
انه حلم يتحقق ان اكون جزء من هذه الجوقة
as I've never been part of one.
حيث اني لم اكن جزء من واحدة من قبل
When I placed a marker on the Google Earth Map,
عندما وضعت علامة على خريطة قوقل ايرث
I had to go with the nearest city, which is about 400 miles away from where I live.
كان علي الذهاب الى اقرب مدينة التي على بعد حوالي 650 كيلومترا من حيث اسكن
As I am in the Great Alaskan Bush,
اذ انا في ادغال الاسكا العظمى
satellite is my connection to the world."
القمر الصناعي هو وصلتي مع العالم"
So two things struck me deeply about this.
اذن شيئان صدماني عميقا عن هذا
The first is that human beings
الاول ان البشر
will go to any lengths necessary
سيذهبون اي مسافة ضرورية
to find and connect with each other.
ليجدو و يتصلو مع الاخرين
It doesn't matter the technology.
التكنولوجيا غير مهمة
And the second is
و الثاني هو
that people seem to be experiencing an actual connection.
يبدو ان الناس يجربون الاتصال الفعلي
It wasn't a virtual choir.
لم تكن الجوقة الافتراضية
There are people now online that are friends; they've never met.
هنالك اشخاص على الانترنت الان اصدقاء و لم يلتقو ببعض ابدا
But, I know myself too, I feel
و لكن انا اعرف نفسي ايضا اشعر
this virtual esprit de corps, if you will, with all of them.
بروح العمل الجماعي الافتراضية هذه اذا صح التعبير معهم كلهم
I feel a closeness to this choir --
اشعر بالقرب من هذه الجوقة
almost like a family.
تقريبا كعائلة
What I'd like to close with then today
ما اريد ان اختم به اليوم
is the first look
هو نظرة اولى
at "Sleep" by Virtual Choir 2.0.
على (النوم) للجوقة الافتراضية النسخة الثانية
This will be a premiere today.
هذا سيكون اول عرض اليوم
We're not finished with the video yet.
لم ننته من الفيديو بعد
You can imagine, with 2,000 synchronized YouTube videos,
يمكنكم التخيل مع 2000 فيديو متزامن من يوتيوب
the render time is just atrocious.
يجعل التوقيت عمل فظيع
But we do have the first three minutes.
لكن لدينا اول ثلاث دقائق
And it's a tremendous honor
و انه لشرف عظيم
for me to be able to show it to you here first.
بالنسبة لي ان استطيع ان اقدمه لكم هنا اولا
You're the very first people to see this.
انتم اوائل الناس لترو هذا
This is "Sleep," the Virtual Choir.
هذه (النوم) للجوقة الافتراضية
(Video) Virtual Choir: ♫ The evening hangs ♫
♫المساء توقف♫
♫ beneath the moon ♫
♫تحت القمر♫
♫ A silver thread on darkened dune ♫
♫خيط من الفضة على الكثبان المظلمة♫
♫ With closing eyes and resting head ♫
♫مع اغلاق العينين و رأس يستريح♫
♫ I know that sleep is coming soon ♫
♫انا اعلم ان النوم ات قريبا♫
♫ Upon my pillow, ♫
♫على وسادتي♫
♫ safe in bed, ♫
♫امن في السرير♫
♫ a thousand pictures fill my head ♫
♫الاف الصور تملأ رأسي♫
♫ I cannot sleep ♫
♫لا استطيع النوم♫
♫ my mind's aflight ♫
♫عقلي طائرة♫
♫ and yet my limbs seem made of lead ♫
♫لكن اطرافي يبدو انها مصنوعة من الرصاص♫
♫ If there are noises in the night ♫
♫اذا كان هناك ضجيج في الليل♫
Eric Whitacre: Thank you very, very much. Thank you.
شكرا جزيلا شكرا شكرا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you very much. Thank you. Thank you.
شكرا جزيلا، شكرا ، شكرا لكم